## **CURRICULUM VITAE.**

# **Personal Details**

Name: AMBROSE ADEYA AHAWO

Address: P.O. BOX 00100 NAIROBI

Email: Ahawoadeya995@gmail.com

Mobile Number: +254729097858

Nationality: KENYAN

Linked In: **AMBROSE AHAWO** 

GitHub: AMBROSE ADEYA AHAWO

# **Personal Statement**

I'm a hardworking and committed individual, able to work as part of a team. I have completed my four-year study at Moi University studying Bachelor of Science in Informatics (Developing and Maintaining information Systems) and I'm looking for this great opportunity to practice my skills.

I have a wide range of Information and Communication Technology skills and I am looking to secure a challenging new role where skills, knowledge and previous experience can be applied and further professional development achieved.

## **Education and Qualifications.**

Moi University: Bachelor of Science in Informatics (Information Systems) – 2016 to 2021.

- Acquired a digital skills certification in partnership with E-Mobilis and Google.
- ♣ I have explored interesting topics on data structures and algorithms.
- Acquired a basic computer programming certificate. (Python and JavaScript)
- Educated and coached on communication skills, report writing and research skills.
- ♣ Did a project and developed a job-seeking system which I'm still improving on, available on my GitHub page.

St. Mary's School Yala: Secondary School Diploma—Dates: 7th February 2012- 5th November 2015.

**♣** Graduated with a mean grade of B+.

#### Key Information Technology Skills:

- Software development with web technologies.
- ♣ Database, data extraction, data cleaning, data visualizations.

#### Key Programming Languages;

- ♣ JavaScript (HTLM, CSS inclusive)
- ♣ NodeJS MERN Stack
- ♣ Python (for backend applications using Django, for data extraction applications using the scrapy library)

## **Work Experience**

Siaya Institute of Technology: *Software and Hardware Support* (June 2021 to September 2021)

Upwork Freelancing Platform: *Full Stack Developer (Reactjs with Python-Django)*, May 2020 to Present (FREELANCE) – <u>check my 5-star ratings</u>.

- ♣ Mastered work ethics and how to handle deadlines when working on projects.
- ♣ Perfected my python programming skills specifically building web scrapping bots.

Libro Systems Kenya: *Hardware Repair and Web Design*, February 2020 to April 2020 (INTERN)

- ♣ Web development and Internet based solutions, which include portals, dynamic websites, multimedia rich interactive websites with Flash and Intranet based solutions for Business Automation
- ♣ PC Hardware repair
- **Remote services**

Moscom Cybercafe: *Hardware Support and Customer Assistance*, August 2017 to December 2017. (INTERN)

- ♣ My main responsibility was to ensure smooth operations of the hardware equipment in the cybercafé.
- ♣ Additionally, I had the duty to ensure satisfaction and user-friendly environment for the customers.
- → During this short experience, I improved on my interpersonal communication skills as I had to communicate with my seniors on arising matters.
- ♣ Directed on the day-to-day operations, which got me sharpen my management skills.

# References.

- 1. Dr. Julia Korongo Moi University Lecturer
  - ➡ Jkorongo@gmail.com
- 2. Mr. Moses Manager at Moscom Cybercafe.
- 3. Mr. Adams Libro Systems Kenya.